A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Beverley Randolph, 1788-1791
Library of Virginia
Additional significant correspondence includes the following: Edmund Randolph to the Council of State regarding his leaving office (1788 Nov. 17); the Judges of the General Court enclosing a list of persons convicted of capital offenses (1788 Dec. 16); John Blair accepting his commission as a judge of the Court of Appeals (1789 Jan. 16); John Dawson regarding the Convention of Kentucky on the navigation of the Mississippi and surrendering the river to Spain (1789 Jan. 29); Martin Oster, French Consul regarding the controversy between Henry Cugneau & Jean Alexis Subercaseaux and John Cauvey (1789 Jan. 31, 1789 March 2 & 22); William Fleming & Peter Lyons regarding their appointments as Judges of the Court of Appeals (1789 Feb. 10); Paul Carrington regarding his appointment to the General Court (1789 Feb. 20); Cyrus Griffin regarding the appointment of William Davies (1789 March 9); Andrew Dunscomb to Davies regarding job & salary (1789 March 17); William Russell regarding the relinquishment to the public of the Capitol Square in Williamsburg and the buildings thereon (1789 May 1); a letter from James Madison, President of Board of Directors, regarding funds to support the Lunatic Hospital in Williamsburg (1789 June 7); Samuel McDowell regarding a remonstrance from inhabitants of the District of Kentucky against discharging the militia from service (1789 July 36); John Hancock regarding the conveyance of the bodies of James Brown & William Davis charged with piracy (1789 Sept. 13); David Ross recommending Piomingo, Chief of the Chickasaws, to pass through the country to New York (1789 Oct. 12); Patrick Henry regarding rifles & expenses for Indians (1789 Oct. 27); John Fitzgerald enclosing an address of the people of Georgetown & Alexandria on the advantages of the Potomac River for the permanent seat of the Federal Government (1789 Dec. 22); George Nicholas regarding his appointment as Attorney General for the District of Kentucky (1790 Jan. 30); William Tatham regarding Hutchin's map, etc. (1790 Feb. 24, April 13, & Aug. 10); James Taylor concerning the proceedings of the Commissioners of the Marine Hospital (1790 March 26, 1790 Oct. 9, & 1791 May 18); Thomas Newton, Jr., regarding a plat of the 2 acres for the Cape Henry Lighthouse (1790 July 25); Simon Fraser regarding an attempt to burn the town of Petersburg (1790 Aug. 10); Gov. J.E. Howard, Maryland, regarding the erection of a lighthouse and disposal of the materials provided for the construction (1791 Jan. 7); Thomas Newton, Jr., regarding McComb's excavation for the lighthouse (1791 July 18); John McComb regarding the foundation for the lighthouse at Cape Henry (1791 July 22); Thomas Johnson, David, Stuart, & Daniel Carroll regarding a draft for the construction of the federal buildings (1791 Aug. 2); David Stuart regarding financial problems in constructing the federal buildings (1791 Aug. 5); and James Madison enclosing proceedings of the Directors of the Hospital for Lunatics (1791 Oct. 26).
Other noteworthy items include: an act regarding the credentials of the senators (1788 Dec. 28); a court order recommending Wilson Cary Nicholas as county lieutenant of Albemarle Co. (1789 Jan. 8); the bond of William Lindsay as Naval Officer of the Elizabeth River District (1789 Feb. 23); a return of the State Electoral College & election certificates from the first Presidential election (1789 Feb.); a report of the Committee as to the Removal into the New Capitol regarding apartments (1789 June 9); proclamations by the Governor (1789 June 5, 1789 July 21, 1791 May 3); the sales at auction of the State Boats Liberty & Patriot by Capt. Richard Taylor (1789 Aug. 6); the oath of allegiance to Cyrus Griffin as Privy Councilor (1789 Oct. 29); oath of allegiance to Charles Carter as Privy Councilor (1789 Nov. 30); a report of the committee regarding appropriations for the building of the Capitol in Richmond (1789 Dec. 14); an account with Bassett Mosely to construct the lighthouse at Cape Henry (1790 Jan. 9); the report of Lt. Gov. James Wood regarding the lighthouse (1790 Jan. 13); the oath of Thomas Madison as Privy Councilor (1790 Jan. 19); the meeting of the Directors of the Lunatic Hospital regarding the resignations of John Blair & James Innes (1790 Feb. 16); the deed of cession from Virginia to the United States for 2 acres of land at Cape Henry for the purpose of erecting a lighthouse (1790 Aug. 9); a proclamation of President George Washington of a treaty between the U.S. and Creek Nation (1790 Aug. 13); and a speech of George Washington regarding public credit, the District of Kentucky & statehood, Indian incursions on frontier settlements, etc. (1790 Dec. 8).
Series II: Subject Files. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject and relates to the Point of Fork Arsenal in Fluvanna Co., Virginia. The series contains accounts of cash & provisions, pay rolls of artificers & state guard, quarterly accounts of muskets, quarter master stores, & clothing, returns of ordnance & military stores, and vouchers between 1789 and 1791. Note that not all materials related to the Point of Fork Arsenal have been separated to this series. Correspondence related to the Arsenal can be found in Series I.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Series I is arranged chronologically by date of document and Series II is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Organization
Organized into two (2) series: I. Chronological Files and II. Subject Files.
Contents List
- Series I: Chronological Files, 1788-1791
- 1788
  - November
    - 10-20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 22-31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1789
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 12-19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - February
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 21-27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Presidential Electors, Jan.-Feb. 1789 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - March
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 12-31 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 22-30 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - May
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 22-30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 22-30 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - July
    - 2-20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 21-31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - August
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 11-31 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - September
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 11-18 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 21-30 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - October
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 17-31 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - November
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 12-20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 23-30 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 12-19 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1790
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 11-20 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 24-31 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - February
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 16-28 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - March
    - 1-20 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 22-30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 12-22 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 23-30 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - May
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 11-19 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 12-20 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 21-30 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - July
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 21-20 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - August
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - 11-19 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - September
    - 1-9 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - 14-28 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - October
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 22-30 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - November
    - 1-20 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 21-30 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 11-20 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 21-31 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Revisal of Laws (Box 5, Folder 10)
- 1791
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 14-20 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 22-29 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - February
    - 1-18 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - 21-26 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - March
    - 1-18 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - 21-31 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - April
    - 2-15 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 22-29 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - May
    - 2-18 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 22-31 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - June
    - 1-14 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 15-30 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - July
    - 1-20 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 21-30 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - August
    - 2-20 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 21-29 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - September
    - 1-9 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 12-29 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - October
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 12-19 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 21-29 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - November
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - 12-19 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - 24-30 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Series II: Subject Files
  - Point of Fork Arsenal
    - Accounts of Cash, 1789-1791 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Accounts of Provisions, 1789-1791 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1790-1791 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Pay Rolls, 1789-1791 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Quarterly Account of Muskets, 1791 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Quarterly Accounts of Quarter Master Stores, 1789-1791 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Quarterly Summary Accounts of Clothing, 1789-1791 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Returns of Ordnance & Military Stores, 1789-1791 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Vouchers for Provisions, 1789-1790 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Oversized (Clamshell Boxes)
  - 1788
    - Nov. 13 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Nov. 17 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Nov. 22 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Nov. 24 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Dec. 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Dec. 16 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dec. 18 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 19 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Dec. 22 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Dec. 27 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Dec. 30 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - [N.D.] (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1789
    - Jan. 26 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Jan. 29 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Feb. 19 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - March 16 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - March 23 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - May 20 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - May 22 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - May 23 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - May 25 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - June 22 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - June 22 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - July 21 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - July 26 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Aug. 6 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Aug. 8 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Nov. 14 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Nov. 17 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Nov. 18 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Nov. 19 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Nov. 28 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Dec. 12 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Dec. 17 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Dec. 22 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - [N.D.] (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - 1790
    - Jan. 9 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - March 20 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - March 26 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - April 22 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - April 23 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - May 1 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - May 15 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - May 31 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - July 4 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Aug. 9 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Sept. 1 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Sept. 27 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Oct. 12 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Oct. 14 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Nov. 8 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Nov. 9 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Nov. 9 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Nov. 10 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Nov. 18 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Nov. 24 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Nov. 26 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Nov. 26 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Nov. 30 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Dec. 4 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Dec. 16 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Dec. 30 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - [N.D.] (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - 1791
    - Jan. 7 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Feb. 4 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Feb. 18 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Feb. 23 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Feb. 25 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - March 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - March 31 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - April 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - May 10 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - May 10 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - May 11 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - June 6 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - July 1 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - July 7 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - July 20 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Aug. 11 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Aug. 27 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Sept. 9 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Sept. 15 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Sept. 15 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Sept. 29 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Oct. 1 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Oct. 6 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Oct. 12 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Oct. 13 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Oct. 18 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Oct. 24 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Oct. 26 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Nov. 1 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Nov. 2 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Oversized (Newspaper Boxes)
  - 1788
    - Nov. 10 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Nov. 21 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Nov. 24 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 11 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1789
    - Jan. 28 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Feb. 6 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - March 2 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - May 8 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - May 30 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - July 6 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Nov. 9 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Nov. 20 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - [N.D.] (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 1790
    - Jan. 1 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - March 18 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - April 22 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - May 5 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - May 21 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - May 27 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - June 30 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - June & July (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - July 12 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - July 20 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Aug. 13 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Aug. 30 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Nov. 9 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Dec. 7 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Dec. 8 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - 1791
    - March 30 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - June 6 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Oct. 10 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Point of Fork Arsenal
    - Quarterly Accounts of Quarter Master Stores, 1789-1791 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Returns of Ordnance & Military Stores, 1789-1791 (Box 11, Folder 2)